<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Information</name>
		<update version="1.0.0.1">
			<file name="information.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Vibolb/dndcustomcontent/master/campaign-one/information.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	<element name="Draconic Spirit" type="Information" source="DnDCustomContent - Campaign One" id="ID_DNDC1_INFORMATION_SUMMON_DRACONIC_SPIRIT_STATBLOCK">
		<description>
			<p><em>Large Dragon, Neutral</em></p>
			<ul class="unstyled mb">
				<li><strong>Armor Class</strong> 14 + the level of the spell (natural armor)</li>
				<li><strong>Hit Points</strong>50 + 10 for each spell level above 5th (the dragon has a number of hit dice [d10s] equal to the level of the spell).</li>
				<li><strong>Speed</strong> 30 ft., fly 60 ft. (Air only), swim 30 ft. (Water only)</li>
			</ul>
			<table style="text-align:center">
				<thead>
					<tr><td>STR</td><td>DEX</td><td>CON</td><td>INT</td><td>WIS</td><td>CHA</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>19 (+4)</td><td>14 (+2)</td><td>17 (+3)</td><td>10 (+0)</td><td>14 (+2)</td><td>14 (+2)</td></tr>
			</table>
			<ul class="unstyled mb">
				<li><strong>Damage Resistances(Chromatic and Metallic Only)</strong> acid, cold, fire, lightning, poison</li>
				<li><strong>Damage Resistances(Gem Only)</strong> force, necrotic, psychic, radiant, thunder</li>
				<li><strong>Condition Immunities</strong> charmed, frightened, poisoned</li>
				<li><strong>Senses</strong> blindsight 30 ft., darkvision 60 ft., passive Perception 12</li>
				<li><strong>Languages</strong> Draconic, understands the languages you speak</li>
				<li><strong>Challenge — Proficiency Bonus (PB)</strong> equals your bonus</li>
				<li><strong>
					Shared Resistances</strong> When you summon the dragon, choose one of its damage resistances. 
					You have resistance to the chosen damage type until the spell ends
				</li>
			</ul>
			<h5 class="caption">ACTIONS</h5>
			<p><strong><em>Multiattack.</em></strong> 
				The dragon makes a number of Rend attacks equal to half the 
				spell's level (rounded down), and it uses Breath Weapon.
			</p>
			<p><strong><em>Rend.</em></strong> 
				Melee Weapon Attack: your spell attack modifier to hit, 
				reach 10 ft., one target. Hit: 1d6 plus 4 + the spell's level piercing damage.
			</p>
			<p><strong>Breath Weapon.</strong> 
				The dragon exhales destructive energy in a 30-foot cone. 
				Each creature in that area must make a Dexterity saving throw against your spell save DC.
				A creature takes 2d6 damage of a type this dragon has resistance to (your choice) on a 
				failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.
			</p>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name="Fused armor" type="Information" id="ID_DNDC1_INFORMATION_FUSED_ARMOR" source="DnDCustomContent - Campaign One">
		<description>
			<p>
				Fused armor means that any armor you are wearing 
				when the fusion happens disappears and becomes the aformentionned item in its 
				unmanifested state. Any armor stat relative to the original armor's type
				is replaced by the fused item's armor stats, if it has any. Refer to the armor's 
				manifested state information for its armor type and stats in that state.
			</p>
	</description>
	</element>
</elements>