<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
    <name>Supernatural Gifts</name>
    <update version="1.0.0.1">
    <file url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Vibolb/zambonidnd/master/campaign-one/items-gifts.xml" name="items-gifts.xml"/>
    </update>
    </info>
    <element name="Aratrh'Oa's Blessing" id="ID_DNDC1_MAGIC_ITEM_ARATHROAS_BLESSING" source="zambonidnd - campaign one" type="Magic Item">
        <description>
        <p>
            <ul>
                <li>
                    Your influence on the fabric of reality deepens. Your maximum inspiration point is 
                    now three. You can spend two inspiration points to generate the following effect:
                    <ul>
                        <li>
                            <strong>“I know someone who…”.</strong> In any situation where it makes sense, you can 
                            spend two inspiration points and declare “I know someone who…”, then quickly 
                            sketch that NPC and your relationship with them (the fewer details the better, 
                            as it leaves room for the DM and other PC to chime in). The DM as the final 
                            say as to what is true or not from the sketched description. Upon declaration, 
                            the NPC exists. Then, when you try to interact with them, you make an 
                            appropriate Charisma check to determine how they react to you.
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li>
                    You may now gain level in the Dragon Knight class and pick Aratrh'Oa the Sea Dragon as your Dragonlord.
                </li>
                <li>
                    As long as your physical appearance does not significantly change, water elemental 
                    brought into existence by Aratrh'Oa's dragon magic will recognize you. At your demand, 
                    they may bring you to her if they don't have a reason not to.
                </li>
                <li> Over the next few days following drinking her artificial and chemically 
                    enhanced blood, your body and mind underwent transformations to better 
                    embody your essence. 
                    <ul>
                        <li>
                            You may modify your starting ability scores following these rules:
                            <ul>
                                <li>
                                    You still use the point buy method.
                                </li>
                                <li>
                                    Your minimum and maximum ability score (before racial and other bonus) 
                                    are still 8 and 15 respectively.
                                </li>
                                <li>
                                    You can't lower an existing score by more than two.
                                </li>
                                <li>
                                    You may now spend 28 points instead of 27 (which would generally total to -1/27 ability 
                                    points in Aurora, for a level 5 character).
                                </li>
                            </ul>
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            That transformation was initially too brutal for some of you, luckily the seizure was 
                            stopped quickly to prevent death or worst. Consequences of this have yet to be discovered…
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
            </ul>
        </p>
        </description>
        <setters>
        <set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
        <set name="type">Boon</set>
        <set name="slot">gift</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
</elements>