<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Wondrous items</name>
		<update version="1.0.3">
			<file name="items-wondrous.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Vibolb/dndcustomcontent/master/campaign-one/items-wondrous.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	
	<!-- place your elements here -->
	<element type="Magic Item" source="DnDCustomContent - Campaign One" id="ID_DNDC1_WONDROUS_ITEM_BAND_OF_EQUANIMITY" name="Band of Equanimity">
		<description>
			<p> While attuned to this item: </p>
			<p>
				<list type="bullet">
					<p>
						<item>
							<strong><em>Once per long rest</em></strong>, you may use your reaction, which you take when you are hit by a weapon or spell attack, to add your spellcasting modifier, to your AC. 
						</item>
					</p>
					<p>
						<item>
							<strong><em>Once per short rest</em></strong>, you can broadcast a telepathic message of no more than 30 words and no longer than 30 seconds to up to 6 willing creates that you can see within 30 feet of you. 
						</item>
					</p>
				</list>
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0.25">0.25 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">head</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element type="Magic Item" source="DnDCustomContent - Campaign One" id="ID_DNDC1_WONDROUS_ITEM_AGONIZING_DRYADS_HEART" name="Agonizing Dryad's Heart">
		<description>
			<p>Attuning to this item causes the heart to merge with your body, effectively replacing your own and granting you the following:</p>
			<p>
				<p>
					You can speak, read and write Sylvan. 
				</p>
				<p>
					You gain the ability to innately cast the <em>Druidcraft</em> cantrip at will. You also gain the ability to innately cast <em>Speak with Animals</em> once per long rest. 
				</p>
				<p>
					<strong><em>Otherwordly Charm: </em></strong> if you spend one minute interacting with a target within 30 feet of you that can see you, you can force it to make a Wisdom saving throw against your spell save DC. On a failure, the target becomes charmed by you for 1 hour or until someone in your party harms it. The creature has no indication that you tried to charm it. Creatures that are immune to being charmed automatically succeed on the saving throw. Once you use this feature, you cannot use it again until you finish a long rest.
				</p>
				<p>
					<strong><em>At 4th level: </em></strong> you can innately cast <em>Lesser Restoration</em> on yourself once per long rest. 
				</p>
				<p>
					<p><strong><em>At 6th level: </em></strong> you gain the following benefits:</p>
					<p>
						<ul>
							<li>You can innately cast <em>Plant Growth</em> once per long rest.</li>
							<li>While your current hit points are below your maximum hit points and you are not incapacitated, you recover 3 hit points at the start of your turn. You must be in direct sunlight to to receive this benefit. You recover 4 hit points at 14th level and 5 hit points at 18th level.</li>
						</ul>
					</p>
				</p>
				<p>
					<strong><em>At 14th level</em></strong> you have advantage on saving throws against being charmed, and you can now use your <em>Otherworldly Charm</em> feature <em>twice per long rest</em>. Additionally, you gain resistance to poison.
				</p>
				<p>
					<p><strong><em>Nature's Shroud: </em></strong> At 18th level, once per long rest, as a bonus action and on your turn, you may gain the following benefits for 1 minute:</p>
					<p>
						<ul>
							<li>You are invisible until you attack or cast a spell. You have advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects.</li>
							<li>You have resistance to damage caused by spells and other magical effects. </li>
							<li>Creatures that target you directly with an attack or a harmful, targeted spell - excluding area-of-effect spells - must make a Wisdom saving throw against your spell save DC. On a failed save, the creature must choose a new target or forfeit targeting someone, potentially wasting the attack or spell. On a successful save, the creature is immune to this effect for 24 hours. Creatures that are immune to being charmed automatically succeed on the saving throw.</li>
						</ul>
					</p>
				</p>
				<p>
					<p><strong><em>Curse.</em></strong> This item is cursed and afflicts you with the dying dryad's fears and despair:</p>
					<p>
						<ul>
							<li>You cannot voluntarily end attunement to this item.</li>
							<li>Forcibly removing the heart removes your heart in the process.</li>
							<li>Thorns dig into your inner organs, reducing your hit point maximum by 1/player level.</li>
							<li>You are vulnerable to fire. Additionally, after taking fire damage, you must succeed a Wisdom saving throw with a DC equal to 10 or half the received damage, whichever is higher. On a failed save, you are Frightened by the damage’s source for 1 minute. You can repeat the save at the end of your turn, ending the effect on a success.</li>
							<li>The heart’s despair flows through your veins, you have Disadvantage on saving throws against being Frightened.</li>
							<li>Voluntarily harming plants or beasts or letting it happen unless for self-defense, survival or nature’s greater good - at your DM's discretion - requires you to make a DC 14 Charisma saving throw. On a failed save, you take 1d6 psychic damage. Failing this save frequently can lead to short- and long-term madness.</li>
						</ul>
					</p>
				</p>
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot" />
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element type="Magic Item" source="DnDCustomContent - Campaign One" id="ID_DNDC1_WONDROUS_ITEM_CELESTIAL_GUARDIANS_STARLIGHT_CLOAK" name="Celestial Guardian`s Starlight Cloak">
		<description>
			<p><em>Seek wisdom from heavenly bodies as our forefathers did. Listen to their song, and dance with them as they fall.</em></p>
			<p>
				<p>
					This deep purple cloak is hemmed with a silver lining that radiates into starburst patterns around the head and arms. 
					When in darkness, tiny stars can be seen from within the cloak's fabric. A constellation of stars in the shape of an 
					eye can always be seen on the front of the cloak's dramatic hood. While wearing the cloak, you can embody a <em><strong>Starry Form </strong></em>
					and <em><strong>Commune with the Stars</strong></em>.
				</p>
				<p>
					<em><strong>Commune with the Stars</strong></em>
				</p>
				<p>
					While you can see the night sky and are wearing the cloak, you can use an action to cast the <italic>Augury</italic> spell. When you do,
					the omens are represented by the number of shooting stars that appear in the sky:
					<list type="bullet">
						<p>
							<item>
								<strong><em>Three or more shooting stars</em></strong>, for good results 
							</item>
						</p>
						<p>
							<item>
								<strong><em>One shooting star</em></strong>, for bad results 
							</item>
						</p>
						<p>
							<item>
								<strong><em>Two shooting stars</em></strong>, for good and bad results 
							</item>
						</p>
						<p>
							<item>
								<strong><em>Nothing</em></strong>, for results that are not especially good or bad
							</item>
						</p>
					</list>
					<p>
						Once this property of the cloak has been used, it cannot be used again until the next dusk.
					</p>
				</p>
			</p>
		</description>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20200224_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STARS_STARRY_FORM" />
		</rules>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="2">1 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot" />
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element  type="Magic Item" source="DnDCustomContent - Campaign One" id="ID_DNDC1_WONDROUS_ITEM_LINGERING_CANDLE_HOLDER" name="Lingering Candle Holder">
		<description>
			<p><em>
				Legend has it that Adeila could not bear the loss of her lover, Angmar, and became hateful toward the concept of transience itself.
				She created ever-enduring objects that eventually outlasted her and her grief. But nothing is ever forever. The smoke hangs still.
				Lifeless. Its time as a flame has come and go, and now it can finally rest, much like Adeila.
			</em></p>
			<p>
				This pewter candle holder makes your hand feel slightly numb while holding it.
				While holding it, you can use a bonus action to speak its command word, Mavli,
				to cause the candle holder to magically hover just above your shoulder. The holder
				floats back to the ground if anything other than a candle is placed on it. In addition,
				any candle in the holder releases a thin wisp of smoke while lit and its flame is static,
				it never flickers. The smoke hangs motionless in the air, regardless of wind, and dissipates after 6 seconds.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot" />
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">false</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element type="Magic Item" source="DnDCustomContent - Campaign One" id="ID_DNDC1_WONDROUS_ITEM_BLOODHUNT_AMULET" name="Bloodhunt Amulet">
		<supports>Ranger</supports>
		<description>
			<p>
				<em>
					This amulet is imbued with the everlasting sadistic lust of Feras, 
					a legendary lycanthropic Shadar-Kai assassin rumored to be one of Brayzer's 
					founders who preferred to toy with its prey rather than kill them.
				</em>
			</p>
			<p>
				While wearing this pendant, you gain the following:
				<ul>
					<li>
						<strong><em>Fear Smells</em></strong>. You have advantage on any ability check that relies on smell. 
						In addition, you can use an action to focus on a particular scent. When you do, you perceive that smell 
						visually as a cloud of red vapor for up to 1 hour. Once this property of the amulet has been used, it 
						can't be used again until the next dawn.
					</li>
					<li><strong><em>It's not the thrill of the kill, it's the thrill of the hunt</em></strong>
						When you cast Hunter's Mark, you no longer need to concentrate on the spell, its duration is doubled,
						 you gain a +1 attack bonus to hit your quarry and the extra damage is reduced to 1d4. You can only 
						 have one mark active at a time. If you cast this spell a second time while a mark is active, the first
						  one ends. While the mark is active, your eyes have a faint red glow, and you can't remove the sadistic 
						  smirk from your face. Once per long rest, you can eat a full meal's worth of humanoid flesh or insects 
						  to gain a free cast of Hunter's Mark at 1st level. You can't gain a free cast this way if you already 
						  have one.
					</li>
				</ul>
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot" />
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">very rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Fists of the Guiding Star" type="Magic Item" source="DnDCustomContent - Campaign One" id="ID_DNDC1_WONDROUS_ITEM_FISTS_OF_THE_GUIDING_STAR">
		<supports>Monk</supports>
		<description>
			<p>
				<em>
					“When the stars align, we all prevail” - A rallying call heard
					 countless times from Celestial Guardians as they rush into battle 
					 to preserve the natural order of all. 
				</em>
			</p>
			<p>
				Stars and celestial bodies glimmer through these hand wrappings. 
				While wearing these wraps over your hands, you can use a <em>bonus action</em> 
				to spend <strong>1 ki point</strong> to cause small motes of starlight to guide a creature 
				you can see within 30 feet of you, giving it <em>Advantage</em> on the next attack
				roll it makes before the end of your next turn. If that creature's next 
				attack hits, the attack deals extra radiant damage equal to your <em>Martial Arts</em> 
				die + your Wisdom modifier (minimum of 1).
			</p>
			<p>In addition, you can use an action to cast the <em>Light</em> cantrip while wearing these wraps.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_PHB_SPELL_LIGHT" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot" />
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<!-- LIGHT spell -->
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LIGHT" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Sandskin Mantle" type="Magic Item" source="DnDCustomContent - Campaign One" id="ID_DNDC1_WONDROUS_ITEM_SANDSKIN_MANTLE">
		<description>
			<p>
				<em>
					A garment worn by the desert raiders of Tamira, the City of Bones. Woven through 
					an expert act of biomancy from skin and sand, it was designed to protect its wearer's 
					vision during harsh sandstorms and allow them to disappear into the sand-strewn winds 
					of the Sand Ocean. 
				</em>
			</p>
			<p>
				While wearing this garment, are immune to blindness and obscuration when its source is dust, 
				debris, sand, snow, or other particulate matter, <em>but not gases</em>. 
			</p>
			<p>
				Once per long rest, as an action, you can activate the power of the mantle and dissolve into 
				visible particulate matter if you are standing in a cloud of it that is at least your size. 
				When you take this form, you can fly up to a range of 20 feet and are immune to damage except 
				psychic damage and effects that destroy matter like the disintegrate spell. You retain a somewhat 
				humanoid form, allowing you to hide in particles but making it obvious that you are not a natural
				occurrence otherwise. You cannot take actions other than the use of a bonus action to return to 
				your normal state. This effect ends on its own after a number of turns equal to your constitution 
				score.
			</p>
			<p>
				<strong>
					Blinding Cloud
				</strong>
				While in cloud form, you may occupy the same space as another creature. A creature that starts 
				its turn in the same space as you must pass a DC 13 Wisdom saving throw, becoming blinded until
				the start of its next turn on failure. If the creature has no eyes or is protected from particles
				and debris, this has no effect on them.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">cloak, armor, blinding, cloud</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">shoulders</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Captioning Cuff of Reading" type="Magic Item" source="DnDCustomContent - Campaign One" id="ID_DNDC1_WONDROUS_ITEM_CAPTIONING_CUFF_OF_READING">
		<description>
			<p>
				While wearing this platinum ear cuff, you gain the following:
				<p>
					<ul>
						<li>
							Any audible sound or spoken language that you are within earshot of is magically transcribed,
							appearing as unobtrusive, illusory text that only you can see in the corner of your vision. While 
							wearing the cuff, you gain a +2 bonus to Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on hearing, even if 
							you are deafened, as you can sometimes read the transcriptions of sounds that are otherwise inaudible. 
							The transcriptions are written in Common, and vary in size and form depending on the nature of the sound. 
							The text conveys the literal meaning of any spoken language that it transcribes. You can choose to ignore 
							certain sounds and transcriptions, causing the text to vanish, in order to better focus on the ones, you're 
							interested in.	
						</li>
						<li>
							<em>Scribesight</em>: As an action you can channel the knowledge of ancient scribes. 
							For a number of minutes equal to your intelligence modifier (minimum of 1), you
							understand any written language that you see, but you must be touching the 
							surface on which the words are written. It takes about 1 minute to read one page
							of text. This doesn't decode secret messages in a text or a glyph, such as an
							arcane sigil, that isn't part of a written language. You can use this ability
							a number of times per long rest equal to your intelligence modifier (minimum 
							of 1).
						</li>
					</ul>
				</p>
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot" />
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Shadow-touched Boots" type="Magic Item" source="DnDCustomContent - Campaign One" id="ID_DNDC1_WONDROUS_ITEM_SHADOW_TOUCHED_BOOTS">
		<description>
			<p>
				<em>
					Spending too much time in the Shadowfell corrupts even the bravest souls.
					The only way to resist its taint is to embrace it. Infamous illusion 
					mages, thieves, assassins, shamans, and other shadowy people have spent 
					countless years studying and welcoming the Shadow’s touch to gain its 
					power. Shadow-touched people and objects use darkness as a conduit for 
					power and elusiveness.
				</em>
			</p>
			
			<p>
				These pitch-black leather boots adjust automatically to your feet, 
				ensuring a skin-tight fit that enhance your perception of the ground 
				you walk on and reducing noises. While attuned to this item and wearing 
				it, you have three shadow charges which you can spend to do the following:
				<p>
					<ul>
						<li>
							<strong>One with Darkness (1 charge).</strong> You have <em>advantage</em> on stealth 
							checks for 10 minutes.
						</li>
						<li>
							<strong>Shadow Step (1 charge).</strong> When you roll initiative, you can 
							teleport up to 30 feet to a location within 10 feet of a 
							creature you can see, provided both of you are not in bright 
							light. 
						</li>
						<li>
							<strong>Dead Men Tell no Tales (1 charge).</strong> If you deal damage to a 
							creature targeted by Shadow Step on your first turn or that
							is surprised, you can use your bonus action to steal their 
							breath and spirit. The target takes psychic damage equal to 
							your level and cannot speak or make sound until the start of 
							your next turn.
						</li>
					</ul>
				</p>
				You regain one shadow charge when an attacker with advantage misses you, when you 
				critically hit a creature that is not in bright light, and you regain all charges 
				at midnight.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">stealth, boots, shadow</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="2">2 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">feet</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Fireweaver Gloves" type="Magic Item" source="DnDCustomContent - Campaign One" id="ID_DNDC1_WONDROUS_ITEM_FIREWEAVER_GLOVES">
		<description>
			<p>
				<em>
					"My light is that of an endless furnace. I will cast out your 
					darkness and set you and your followers alight!"
				</em>
			</p>
			<p>
				While wearing these fine golden gloves, you can use an action 
				to cast the <em>Produce Flame</em> cantrip from it. You can hold this 
				and other small non-magical flames (such as a torch or candle) as 
				if they were tangible objects, and can sculpt them like clay. Once 
				sculpted, a flame retains its form for 1 minute before returning 
				to normal. A non-magical flame carried in this way burns for 1 hour 
				before dying. If you drop or throw a nonmagical flame, it immediately 
				burns out.
			</p>
			<p>
				When you cast <em>Produce Flame</em> using the gloves, the spell's duration 
				is 1 hour, instead of 10 minutes, and it casts bright light in a 
				20-foot radius and dim light for an additional 20 feet. In addition, 
				you can place the spell's conjured flame on the ground at your feet 
				(no action required). When you do, the flame continues to burn harmlessly 
				for up to 1 minute before going out. While you're within 5 feet of the 
				placed flame, you can use an action to pick it back up. When you attack 
				with the flame, you can target objects, and it ignites flammable objects 
				in the area that aren't being worn or carried.
			</p>
			<p>
				In addition, when you take fire damage while wearing these gloves, 
				you can use your reaction to reduce the damage by <em>1d8 + 2</em>.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">fire, gloves</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">hands</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="All-purpose Tool, +1" type="Magic Item" source="DnDCustomContent - Campaign One" id="ID_DNDC1_WONDROUS_ITEM_ALL_PURPOSE_TOOL_+1">
		<description>
			<p>
				This simple screwdriver can transform into a variety of tools; 
				as an action, you can touch the item and transform it into any 
				type of artisan's tool of your choice (see the "Equipment" chapter 
				in the <em>Player's Handbook</em> for a list of artisan's tools). Whatever 
				form the tool takes, you are proficient with it. While holding this 
				tool, you gain a bonus to the spell attack rolls and the saving throw 
				DCs of your artificer spells. The bonus is determined by the tool's rarity.
			</p>
			<p>
				As an action, you can focus on the tool to channel your creative forces. 
				Choose a cantrip that you don't know from any class list. For 8 hours, you 
				can cast that cantrip, and it counts as an artificer cantrip for you. Once 
				this property is used, it can't be used again until the next dawn.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">wondrous, tool, all-purpose, artificer</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">1500</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">feet</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by an artificer">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="All-purpose Tool, +2" type="Magic Item" source="DnDCustomContent - Campaign One" id="ID_DNDC1_WONDROUS_ITEM_ALL_PURPOSE_TOOL_+2">
		<description>
			<p>
				This simple screwdriver can transform into a variety of tools; 
				as an action, you can touch the item and transform it into any 
				type of artisan's tool of your choice (see the "Equipment" chapter 
				in the <em>Player's Handbook</em> for a list of artisan's tools). Whatever 
				form the tool takes, you are proficient with it. While holding this 
				tool, you gain a bonus to the spell attack rolls and the saving throw 
				DCs of your artificer spells. The bonus is determined by the tool's rarity.
			</p>
			<p>
				As an action, you can focus on the tool to channel your creative forces. 
				Choose a cantrip that you don't know from any class list. For 8 hours, you 
				can cast that cantrip, and it counts as an artificer cantrip for you. Once 
				this property is used, it can't be used again until the next dawn.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">wondrous, tool, all-purpose, artificer</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">5000</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">feet</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by an artificer">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="All-purpose Tool, +3" type="Magic Item" source="DnDCustomContent - Campaign One" id="ID_DNDC1_WONDROUS_ITEM_ALL_PURPOSE_TOOL_+3">
		<description>
			<p>
				This simple screwdriver can transform into a variety of tools; 
				as an action, you can touch the item and transform it into any 
				type of artisan's tool of your choice (see the "Equipment" chapter 
				in the <em>Player's Handbook</em> for a list of artisan's tools). Whatever 
				form the tool takes, you are proficient with it. While holding this 
				tool, you gain a bonus to the spell attack rolls and the saving throw 
				DCs of your artificer spells. The bonus is determined by the tool's rarity.
			</p>
			<p>
				As an action, you can focus on the tool to channel your creative forces. 
				Choose a cantrip that you don't know from any class list. For 8 hours, you 
				can cast that cantrip, and it counts as an artificer cantrip for you. Once 
				this property is used, it can't be used again until the next dawn.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">wondrous, tool, all-purpose, artificer</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">20000</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">feet</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by an artificer">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Gaas' Unworldly Coat" type="Magic Item" id="ID_DNDC1_WONDROUS_ITEM_GAAS_UNWORLDLY_COAT" source="DnDCustomContent - Campaign One">
		<description>
			<p>
				<em>
					If you gaze long enough into other worlds, the other worlds also gaze into you.
				</em>
			</p>
			<p>
				A jet-black coat that glimmers of green and blue
				hues under sunlight and moonlight, seemingly absorbing 
				and emanating colors at the same time. This unnatural 
				phenomenon is captivating and sparks curiosity at first 
				sight. After looking at it for more than a few seconds 
				straight, people start hearing soft undecipherable 
				screech and feeling observed by semblance of inhuman 
				eyes shimmering on it, most of them look away, troubled,
				at that point.
			</p>
			<p>
				While wearing this coat, Gaas:
			</p>
			<p>
				<ul>
					<li>
						Can mentally send messages to 
						willing creatures within 30 feet,  
						up to X creatures and 10 times X 
						words at a time, where X is its 
						intelligence modifier. This communication 
						is one-way only. The use of this feature 
						may attract the unwanted attention of 
						otherworldly beings.
					</li>
					<li>
						May spend 1 hour concentrating during 
						a short rest to know the general direction 
						to the closest Fey Crossing and Shadow Crossing
						within a 60-mile radius. This does not 
						prevent him for regaining hit points with 
						hit dice as it is a light activity. The use 
						of this feature may attract the unwanted 
						attention of otherworldly beings.
					</li>
					<li>
						Has advantage on saving throws against Shadowfell Despair.
					</li>
				</ul>
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">gaas, coat, cloak, fey, wild</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="2">2 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">shoulders</set>
			<set name="type" addition="combat coat">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Vestment of the Breathless" type="Magic Item" id="ID_DNDC1_WONDROUS_ITEM_VESTMENT_OF_THE_BREATHLESS" source="DnDCustomContent - Campaign One">
		<description>
			<p><em>
				Breathing techniques were invented by the last 
				few martial arts masters standing before the 
				world had to be submerged to vanquish the abyssal 
				invasion that brought it to its knees centuries ago. 
				Breath flows like Ki and allows the body, the mind, 
				and the soul to connect and synchronise to unlock 
				their hidden capabilities.
			</em></p>
			<p>
				This vestment made of intricate leather straps 
				contracts your body in a way that forces you to 
				constantly practice breathing exercises, allowing 
				your body to accomplish much more than the average 
				person would with the same amount of oxygen. 
				While wearing this vestment, you are under the 
				effect of the Breathless Renewal breathing technique 
				at all times. You can only practice one breathing 
				technique at once.
			</p>
			<p>
				<strong>
					Breathless Renewal
				</strong>
				<ul>
					<li>
						<strong>Flowing Ki</strong>. Using Patient 
						Defense and Step of the Wind increases 
						your movement speed by 5 feet until the 
						beginning of your next turn. When using 
						either of these techniques, you may roll 
						your martial art dice. If the result is 
						higher than the number of Ki point you 
						have left and different from 1, you 
						regain the spent Ki point. 
					</li>
					<li>
						<strong>Perfect Movements</strong>. Being able  
						to move at inhumane speed and precision allow 
						you to use your agility and speed to overcome 
						obstacles usually dealt with brute force. Once 
						per short rest, when prompted to roll for an 
						Athletics check, you can roll for Acrobatics 
						instead. When this feature has been used, you 
						can spend a Ki point to use it again.
					</li>
					<li>
						<strong>Less is More</strong>. Double the amount 
						of time for which you can hold your breath.
					</li>
				</ul>
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">breath, vestment</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="2">2 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">shoulders</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Ean'el's Undying Tunic" type="Magic Item" id="ID_DNDC1_WONDROUS_ITEM_EANEL_UNDYING_TUNIC" source="DnDCustomContent - Campaign One">
		<description>
			<p><em>
				The important thing is this: to be able, 
				at any moment, to sacrifice what we are for 
				what we could become.
			</em></p>
			<p>
				The pale beige of this tunic and the bright bleu 
				of its intricate 4-petaled tulip symbol never tarnish, 
				and always smells like fresh flowery spring breeze. 
				It brings you closer to the dead yet protects you 
				from death, while championing selflessness. 
			</p>
			<p>
				While wearing it, Ean'el:
				<ul>
					<li>
						Rarely feels hungry or thirsty 
						and only needs to consume one-fifth the 
						usual amount of food and water required 
						to thrive.
					</li>
					<li>
						May, once per day, use an action to meditate 
						and detect the presence of the dead. For 1 
						minute or until your concentration ends,
						- as if you were concentrating on a spell - 
						you know the direction of any undead creature 
						and corpse within 30 feet of you. You also know 
						if there is a place or object within that range 
						that has been magically desecrated. This effect 
						can penetrate most barriers, but it is blocked 
						by 1 foot of stone, 1 inch of common metal, a 
						thin sheet of lead, or 3 feet of wood or dirt.
					</li>
					<li>
						May, as an action, pluck one of the 4 tulip's 
						petal and use it to heal a target for 1d4 hit points 
						at touch range. The petal withers if it is not used 
						during Ean'e's turn. The item regains 1d4 charges at 
						sunrise. Ean'el may also, as a bonus action, replenish 
						1d4+1 charges and gain a level of <em>exhaustion</em> at the 
						end of its turn. The tulip's petal can't be used on 
						himself.
					</li>
					<li>
						Gains a +1 bonus to armor class if he has any levels 
						of <em>exhaustion</em> - the bonus does not increase with exhaustion level.
					</li>
				</ul>
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">undying, Ean'el, tunic, monk</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="2">2 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">shoulders</set>
			<set name="type" addition="monk tunic">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Lilypad Token" type="Magic Item" id="ID_DNDC1_WONDROUS_ITEM_LILYPAD_TOKEN" source="DnDCustomContent - Campaign One">
		<description>
			<p><em>
				A token of remembrance of a peaceful time. Before war, when 
				halflings lived in harmony with giants in their recluse land 
				covered in overgrown trees and immense waterfalls, you could 
				see them drinking the afternoon tea in lilypad boats floating 
				in ponds made by giant's footprints.
			</em></p>
			<p>
				This token made from emerald gemstone floats on water. 
				When you throw it into water and speak its command word 
				while it is floating, it turns into a giant lilypad raft. 
				The lilypad is 10ft. in diameter and can hold up to five 
				creatures or 750 lb., whichever is met first. The creature 
				who spoke the command word can use a bonus action to command 
				it to float towards a direction. The raft does so at a speed 
				of 30ft. per round until it reaches its destination or is 
				commanded to stop. Repeating the command word turns the raft 
				back into a token provided that no creatures are aboard.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">lilypad, token, float, boat</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">50</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0.5">0.5 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Bag of Spellybeans" id="ID_DNDC1_WONDROUS_ITEM_BAG_OF_SPELLYBEANS" type="Magic Item" source="DnDCustomContent - Campaign One">
		<description>
			<p>
				<em>
					“You'd think the green one is mint and the red one strawberry, 
					but honestly I swear these beans seem to be changing colors when 
					you're not looking at them. Watchout for the spicy ones.”
				</em>
			</p>
			<p>
				This bag contains 5d4 beans. The flavor of a bean cannot be identified 
				by its color. Consuming a bean allows you to cast a specific spell at 
				its lowest level once within the next minute. You can take a bean from 
				the bag and consume it as an action. Roll on the table to determine which 
				flavor is has. The spell uses an ability modifier of +2 and a spell attack 
				bonus of +4. If you have a spell slot of the appropriate level or higher, 
				you may expend it when you cast the spell. If you do, you can use your own 
				spellcasting ability modifier and spell attack bonus instead.
			</p>
			<table style="text-align:center">
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Roll</td><td>Flavor</td><td>Spell</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1</td><td>Licorice</td><td>Goodberry</td></tr>
				<tr><td>2</td><td>Strawberry</td><td>Command</td></tr>
				<tr><td>3</td><td>Mint</td><td>Guiding Bolt</td></tr>
				<tr><td>4</td><td>Lemon</td><td>Counterspell</td></tr>
				<tr><td>5</td><td>Cayenne Pepper</td><td>Burning Hands</td></tr>
				<tr><td>6</td><td>Pinepapple</td><td>Acid Arrow</td></tr>
				<tr><td>7</td><td>Cinnamon</td><td>Shield</td></tr>
				<tr><td>8</td><td>Reaper Pepper</td><td>Scorching Ray</td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">beans, spells</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp"></set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Lysander's Everlasting Spark" id="ID_DNDC1_WONDROUS_ITEM_LYSANDERS_EVERLASTING_SPARK" type="Magic Item" source="DnDCustomContent - Campaign One">
		<description>
			<p>
				<em>
					“The very life of any creature is a quick-fading spark in fathomless darkness.”
				</em>
			</p>
			<p>
				A dark vest that generates its own fiery red reflections, it shines brighter as its wearer get closer to death. It cannot be worn over an armor. While wearing it, Lysander:
				<ul>
					<li>
						Can still move, but neither take actions, reactions, or bonus actions, nor talk or make articulated gestures while at 0 hit point. In that state, the tuxedo's fabric displays bright reddish flames en produces volatile firebrands. When he is brought to 0 hit points, he may make a Strength saving throw to stay standing, falling prone on a failure. The DC equals 10 or half the damage taken, whichever is higher. 
					</li>
				</ul>
			</p>
			<p>
				Additionally, when the tuxedo is visible (i.e., not under an armor of other clothes):
				<ul>
					<li>
						He has advantage on charisma checks against undead.
					</li>
					<li>
						Undead are reluctant to approach and target the spark. If an undead targets him directly with an attack or 
						a harmful spell, that creature must make a DC 12 Wisdom saving throw (an undead needn't make the save when 
						it includes you in an area effect, such as the explosion of fireball). On a failed save, the creature must 
						choose a new target or forfeit targeting someone instead of him, potentially wasting the attack or spell. On 
						a successful save, the creature is immune to this effect for 24 hours. An undead is also immune to this effect 
						for 24 hours if he targets or affects it with an attack or a harmful spell.
					</li>
				</ul>
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">spark, lysander, everlasting</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp"></set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">5 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="tuxedo">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Forgekeeper's Spark" id="ID_DNDC1_WONDROUS_ITEM_FORGEKEEPERS_SPARK" type="Magic Item" source="DnDCustomContent - Campaign One">
		<description>
			<p>
				<em>
					The sound of song clattered through the smithy, its tempo and percussion kept by 
					the beating of a hammer against anvil. Most visitors would come and go, thinking 
					the behavior simply charming and good-natured, but the clever ones who looked closely 
					would notice, after a time, that the smith was singing to the fire. His wobbling notes 
					and timed beats created a chorus for he and the spirit within the flames to work and dance 
					to. The smith wasn't singing idly, no: he was serenading his coworker, friend, and muse.
				</em>
			</p>
			<p>
				A lingering fragment of a fire spirit remains attached to this piece of coal, keeping it 
				covered in harmless blue embers that are pleasantly warm to the touch. When surrounded 
				by fire, the coal burns with a magical blue flame and the spirit within it emerges. 
				The spirit remains until the fire goes out or is doused, at which point the spirit hides 
				within its coal until immersed in flames once more. If removed from the fire, the spirit 
				moves with the burning coal and remains for up to 1 minute.
			</p>
			<p>
				While the spirit is present, it helps tend to the fire it's placed in. The spirit can maintain 
				a fire that fills up to a 5-foot cube. A fire tended to by the spirit gains the following benefits:
				<ul>
					<li>
						It can't be extinguished by strong winds.
					</li>
					<li>
						It produces no smoke, unless you want it to.
					</li>
					<li>
						It burns for twice the normal duration with the same amount of fuel.
					</li>
					<li>
						Any food being cooked in the fire is kept at an ideal temperature.
					</li>
				</ul>
			</p>
			<p>
				In addition, you have advantage on any ability check you make that uses either 
				cook's utensils or glassblower's, smith's, or tinker's tools to heat and craft 
				items in the fire. If you roll a 15 or higher on the d20, the time it takes to 
				use the tools in this way is halved.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">spark, forge, coal</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp"></set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Experimental Clockwork Trap" type="Magic Item" source="DnDCustomContent - Campaign One" id="ID_DNDC1_WONDROUS_ITEM_ALL_PURPOSE_TOOL_+3">
		<description>
			<p>
				When you use your Action to rotate the energy crystal at the center 
				of this trap to activate it, it forms three concentric metal rings 
				that snap shut when a creature steps on it. The trap can be affixed 
				by a heavy chain to an immobile object, such as a tree or a spike 
				driven into the ground. A creature that steps on the plate must succeed 
				on a DC 15 Dexterity saving throw or take 1d4 piercing damage plus 1d4 
				lightning damage and stop moving. The trap adapts its color to its environment, 
				requiring a DC 15 Perception check to spot. Thereafter, until the creature breaks 
				free of the trap, its Movement is limited by the length of the chain or other 
				affixing item it is attached to. A creature can use its Action to make a DC 15 
				Strength check, freeing itself or another creature within its reach on a success. 
				Each failed check deals 1 piercing damage and 1d4 lightning damage to the trapped 
				creature. A trapped creature has its movement reduced by 10 feet and take 1d4 lightning 
				damage per 5 feet traveled. A trap has 50% chance of becoming unusable after trapping 
				a creature.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">clock, trap</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp"></set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">false</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
</elements>