<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Weapons</name>
		<update version="1.0.0">
			<file name="items-weapons.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Vibolb/zambonidnd/master/campaign-one/items-weapons.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	
	<!-- place your elements here -->
	<element name="Lex Talionis" id="ID_DNDC1_MAGIC_ITEM_LEX_TALIONIS" source="zambonidnd - campaign one" type="Magic Item">
        <description>
            <p>While attuned to this item <em>and</em> wielding it, the bearer can cast <strong><em>An Eye for an Eye</em></strong> and <strong><em>A Tooth for a Tooth</em></strong> once per long rest.</p>
            <div class="reference">
                <div element="ID_DNDC1_SPELL_AN_EYE_FOR_AN_EYE" />
            </div>
            <div class="reference">
                <div element="ID_DNDC1_SPELL_A_TOOTH_FOR_A_TOOTH" />
            </div>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">dagger</set>
            <set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
            <set name="type" addition="dagger">Weapon</set>
            <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="weapon">Dagger</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_DNDC1_SPELL_AN_EYE_FOR_AN_EYE" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_DNDC1_SPELL_A_TOOTH_FOR_A_TOOTH" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Merciful Macuahuitl" id="ID_DNDC1_MAGIC_ITEM_MERCIFUL_MACUAHUITL" source="zambonidnd - campaign one" type="Magic Item">
        <description>
        <p>
            <em>
                War leaves its marks on everyone who sees it. Some take scars that never heal. So did the leves that had to kill their companions 
                that turned against them during the Titan's war. Their sorrow and their friends' blood drenched these weapons, granting them innate necrotic powers.
            </em>
        </p>
        <p>
            This tribal sword's sturdy wooden frame is lined with obsidian shards, allowing attacks made with it to deal either bludgeoning 
            or slashing damage (your choice). 
        </p>
        <p>
            The sword has been enchanted through the heartbreaking slaughter of friends turned foes. When you roll a 20 on your
            attack roll with this magic weapon against a creature, that creature becomes marked for death until the start of your
            next turn. A marked creature can't regain hit points, does not feel pain, and when the mark ends, takes 1d8 necrotic damage.
        </p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">longsword</set>
            <set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="3">3 lb.</set>
            <set name="type" addition="longsword">Weapon</set>
            <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
            <set name="attunement">false</set>
            <set name="weapon">Longsword</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Vial Dagger" id="ID_DNDC1_MAGIC_ITEM_VIAL_DAGGER" source="zambonidnd - campaign one" type="Magic Item">
        <description>
            <p>
                <em>
                    Shattered jaws may heal in time, but some betrayals fester and poison the soul. 
                </em>
            </p>
            <p>
                This translucent dagger is made of magically reinforced glass. A hidden intricate 
                contraption in its handle makes it usable as a syringe. It takes a minute to carefully 
                fill the syringe with a liquid. Poison inside the vial maintains its potency for 24 
                hours. As part of an attack with the dagger, after you hit, as a free action, you may
                activate the hidden contraption to release all its content in the target. All saving 
                throws against poisons delivered this way have their DC increased by 1. Additionally,
                if the vial is empty, this dagger may be used to harvest venom or blood from a creature
                providing advantage on the check when used in conjunction with a poisoner's kit. 
            </p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">dagger</set>
            <set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
            <set name="type" addition="dagger">Weapon</set>
            <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
            <set name="attunement">false</set>
            <set name="weapon">Dagger</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Harvest" id="ID_DNDC1_MAGIC_ITEM_HARVEST" source="zambonidnd - campaign one" type="Magic Item">
        <description>
            <p>
                <em>
                    Every life, whether human, beast, or plant, must come to an end. 
                    It's all temporary. Everything has its own grim reaper, and 
                    today, I'm ready to reap what's been sown. 
                </em>
            </p>
            <p>
                This wildlands explorer's heirloom depicts wheat and field 
                designs and is so well crafted is has the finesse property. 
                When you hit a plant creature with an attack using this magic 
                weapon, the target takes an extra 1d6 slashing damage. In 
                addition, any nonmagical plant harvested with this sickle 
                magically remains fresh for an extra 7 days.
            </p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">sickle</set>
            <set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="2">2 lb.</set>
            <set name="type" addition="sickle">Weapon</set>
            <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
            <set name="attunement">false</set>
            <set name="weapon">Sickle</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Tribute to Phoenixes" id="ID_DNDC1_MAGIC_ITEM_TRIBUTE_TO_PHOENIXES" source="zambonidnd - campaign one" type="Magic Item">
        <description>
            <p>
                <em>
                    Gnomes pride themselves for works of art and craftmanship that
                     are ingenuously useful during their lifetime. Dwarves strive 
                     to build eternally magnificent figurative masterpieces. This 
                     creation is a tribute to both their traditions, emulating the 
                     phoenix the repeatedly burns gloriously during his never-ending 
                     cycles of life and death. What a poetic heirloom to pass from 
                     generation to generation. 
                </em>
            </p>
            <p>
                This magic sword is made of emberwood, a dark tree that grows only in
                 volcanic regions where the lava veins flow like water beneath the ground. 
                 It looks like a regular wood but is as hard as steel and requires years 
                 of training to smith, let alone craft intricate details and imbue it with 
                 magic. You have a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic 
                 weapon.
            </p>
            <p>
                <strong>Phoenix Dance.</strong> As a bonus action, you can speak this sword 
                command word to make the magic sap within the wood ignite the blade for 
                1 minute or until you dismiss it (no action required). Once you activate 
                the flames within the sword, you can't do it again until the next dawn. 
                When you hit a creature with this magic sword while it is lit, the creature 
                takes an extra 1d4 fire damage. In addition, the magic flames surrounding 
                the sword turn even defensive movements, a threat to the enemies around you. 
                Whenever a creature that is 5ft from you misses you with an attack roll, it 
                takes 1d4 fire damage.
            </p>
            <p>
                <strong>Phoenix Might.</strong> While holding this sword, you can use it as a spellcasting focus.
                 Spells that deal fire damage cast through this focus have a +1 bonus to spell attack rolls 
                 and to their saving throw DCs. Casting a spell that deals fire damage through this sword cause
                 it to inflame at the end of the next X rounds or until it hits a target, dealing an additional
                 Xd4 fire damage on hit, whichever comes first. X equals the level of the spell cast.
            </p>
            <p>
                While the sword is ablaze by any effect, it shines bright light it a 20-foot radius and 
                dim light in an additional 20 feet.
            </p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">sword, short, fire, phoenix</set>
            <set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="2">2 lb.</set>
            <set name="type" addition="shortsword">Weapon</set>
            <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="weapon">Shortsword</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
</elements>