<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Potions</name>
		<description></description>
		<update version="1.0.1">
			<file url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Vibolb/zambonidnd/master/campaign-one/items-potions.xml" name="items-potions.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
    <element name="Potion of Darkvision (Weak Lasting)" type="Magic Item" source="zambonidnd - campaign one" id="ID_DNDC1_MAGIC_ITEM_WEAK_LASTING_POTION_OF_DARKVISION">		
        <description>
            <p>
                <em>
                    Ya think you'll be less afraid of the dark once you know what's in it? Ah! We'll see… well… you will.
                </em>
            </p>
            <p>
                When you drink this potion, you gain darkvision for up to 30 feet for 8 hours. 
                If you drink this and you already have darkvision, its range is increased by 15 feet. 
                Illusory black circles form around the magic-imbued pine nuts floating in this dark purple 
                liquid to create ephemeral feline irises that stare at the closest living being.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">darkvision</set>
            <set name="category">Potions</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">25</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0.5">½ lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Potion</set>
            <set name="rarity">Common</set>
            <set name="stackable">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Spoiled Cocktail of Condensed Energy" type="Magic Item" source="zambonidnd - campaign one" id="ID_DNDC1_MAGIC_ITEM_SPOILED_COCKTAIL_OF_CONDENSED_ENERGY" >
        <description>
            <p>
                Drinking this potion allows you to benefit from a short rest instantly. 
                The maximum of HD you can spend is equal to half your maximum, rounded down. 
                Your movement speed increase by 10 feet.
            </p> 
            <p>
                When you drink this potion, make a 
                Constitution saving throw. The movement speed increase lasts for a number of 
                minutes equal to three times the result of the saving throw, after which you 
                gain one level of exhaustion, and your movement speed is reduced by 10 feet.
            </p> 
            <p>
                The movement speed reduction lasts until you recover from that level of exhaustion. 
                Drinking more than one of these potions between long rests may have adverse effects.
            </p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">energy, cocaine, blue</set>
            <set name="category">Potions</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">180</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0"></set>
            <set name="type">Potion</set>
            <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
            <set name="stackable">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Cocktail of Otherwordly Pleasure" type="Magic Item" source="zambonidnd - campaign one" id="ID_DNDC1_MAGIC_ITEM_COCKTAIL_OF_OTHERWORDLY_PLEASURE" >
        <description>
            <p><em>This colorless translucent and odorless liquid always seems still, even when its container is shaken. </em></p>
            <p>
                A typical flask holds 12 ounces of this liquid. A portion is 3 ounces. As an action, a creature can drink up to 4 portions 
                of this liquid at once. While under the effects of this magical drink, a creature feels a surge of adrenaline, has trouble 
                focusing on many things at once, is disinhibited, and experiences all sensations and emotions much more pleasantly than they 
                actually are. Additional effects are described in the table below. Taking a new sip while already affected produces the effects
                of the sum of portions drank and resets the duration to that of the new total. The side effects are cumulative and last for 
                the duration or until the creature dies.
            </p>
            <p>
                <table style="text-align:center">
                    <thead>
                        <tr><td>Intake</td><td>Duration(minutes)</td><td>Side effects</td></tr>
                    </thead>
                    <tr><td>1</td><td>1</td><td>None</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>2</td><td>2.5</td><td>Invisible, poisoned*, casting spells and maintaining concentration requires concentration check DC 10 + intake</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>3</td><td>5</td><td>-2 on attacks, ability checks and saving throws</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>4</td><td>10</td><td>Constitution save DC 8 + intake or fall unconscious for the duration</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>5</td><td>15</td><td>Hover speed equal to walking speed</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>6</td><td>20</td><td>Speed halved</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>7</td><td>25</td><td>Incorporeal</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>8</td><td>30</td><td>-3 on attacks, ability checks and saving throws</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>8</td><td>+5/potion</td><td>Sees and can communicate with ghosts, loss of consciousness at this level of intake can cause seizure or death</td></tr>
                </table>
            </p>
            <p>* While poisoned this way, a creature also has disadvantage on all saving throws.</p>
            <p>** An incorporeal creature is shunted to the nearest unoccupied space and takes 2d10 force damage if it ends its turn inside an object or a creature.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">energy, pleasure, otherwordly</set>
            <set name="category">Potions</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp"></set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0.5">0.5 lb</set>
            <set name="type">Potion</set>
            <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
            <set name="stackable">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
</elements>