<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Armor</name>
		<update version="1.0.0.1">
			<file name="items-armor.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Vibolb/dndcustomcontent/master/campaign-one/items-armor.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	
	<!-- place your elements here -->
	<element name="Mistwalker Armor" id="ID_DNDC1_MAGIC_ITEM_MISTWALKER_ARMOR" source="DnDCustomContent - Campaign One" type="Magic Item">
        <description>
            <p>
                <em>
                    Seemingly endless heat, horror and death poured from the Abyss' 
                    Maw into the old world during the invasion. Fiends adapted faster
                    than us to the everlasting mist that covered the coast. To 
                    survive, we had to learn how to use their power against them, 
                    and that was through their hide. Put yourself in someone's shoes 
                    or, as some say, skin, and you'll understand them.
                </em>
            </p>
            <p>
                This dark leather armor releases thin wisps of fog from its seams. 
                While wearing this armor, you can use an action to cast the fog cloud 
                spell (2nd-level version) from it. Once this property of the armor 
                has been used, it can't be used again until the next dawn.
            </p>
            <p>
                In addition, fog doesn't obscure your vision, and while you're in 
                opaque fog and use the Dash, Disengage or Dodge action, you can 
                gain the benefit of all three. You can gain the benefit of this 
                feature up to half your level times per long rest. 
            </p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">leather, armor</set>
            <set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="slot">body</set>
            <set name="type" addition="light">Armor</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
            <set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_LIGHT, Leather</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="8">8 lb</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <!-- Fog Cloud spell -->
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FOG_CLOUD" />
        </rules>
        
    </element>
    <element name="Aegis of the Pleased Gods" id="ID_DNDC1_MAGIC_ITEM_AEGIS_OF_THE_PLEASED_GODS" source="DnDCustomContent - Campaign One" type="Magic Item">
        <description>
            <p>
                <em>
                    May it be a light to you in dark places, when all other lights go out.
                </em>
            </p>
            <p>
                This shield emits a faint, holy glow when wielded and recognizes 
                your devotion to a higher power. When you attune to this shield, 
                the emblem adorning its face changes to one that represents your 
                chosen deity, allowing you to use the shield as a holy symbol.
            </p>
            <p>
                While wielding the shield, you can speak its command word 
                as a bonus action to cause it to shatter into countless 
                fragments of pure light. The pieces of light protect you 
                as if you were wielding the shield, leaving your hands free. 
                The light surrounds you for 1 minute, until you dismiss the 
                effect as a bonus action, or until you fall unconscious or die, 
                at which point the shield rematerializes on the ground at your 
                feet or into your hand if you have one free. If your holy symbol 
                is emblazoned or attached to the shield, it floats prominently amidst 
                the shards of light and continues to function as a spellcasting focus. 
                While in this form: 
            </p>
            <p>
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        The shield gives you a +1 bonus to your AC in addition to the shield's 
                        normal bonus to AC. 
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        The surrounding shards of light cast bright light in a 20 foot radius 
                        and dim light for another 20 feet. Undead creatures have disadvantage
                         on attack rolls made against you while you're surrounded by the light
                          in this way. 
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        When you activate this feature, you emit a pulse of blinding divine light.
                        Creatures of your choice in the bright light radius must succeed a 
                        Constitution saving throw or be blinded until the end of your next 
                        turn. The DC equals 8 + twice your Religion bonus. While the light 
                        lasts, at the beginning of your turn, you can emit a new pulse. You 
                        can do that a number of times equals to your proficiency bonus.
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </p>
            <p>Once this property has been used, it can't be used again until the following dawn.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">shield</set>
            <set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="slot">body</set>
            <set name="type" addition="shield">Armor</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="rarity">Rare</set>
            <set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_SHIELD</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="6">6 lb.</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Doain's Prayer of Providence" type="Magic Item" id="ID_DNDC1_ARMOR_DOAINS_PRAYER_OF_PROVIDENCE" source="DnDCustomContent - Campaign One">
        <description>
            <p><em>
                Conviction is worthless unless it is converted into conduct.
            </em></p>
            <p>
                This ample autumnal orange robe that fused with your hide armor
                following Solaris' blessing comes in pair with an oak tree 
                branch and leaves crown. The crawling things of the earth, 
                such as insects, snakes, and vermin, are attracted to this 
                item. When any part of any of its forms is placed on natural 
                ground, such creatures will scurry toward it like moths drawn 
                to the flame.
            </p>
            <p>
                This armor (robe) is naught but a prayer written on a scrap of vellum and 
                decorated with religious scriptures and ornamental oak leaves representing 
                the god Silvanus. Doain may spend 1 minute at to read the prayer out loud. 
                At the end, this armor will manifest and encase him, including the crown. 
                The armor disappears if he acts in any way that is not in accordance with
                Silvanus' teachings. While the armor is manifested, he can utter the prayer 
                to revert it back to its vellum prayer form.
            </p>
            <p>
                While the armor is manifested, he may treat it as a <em>+1 armor</em> when in direct 
                sunlight and has a +1 bonus to <em>performance</em> checks. He loses both of 
                these benefits if the crown is not worn on his head. He always knows the 
                direction of the crown if is on the same plane as him.
            </p>
            <div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_DNDC1_INFORMATION_FUSED_ARMOR" />
			</div>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">armor, hide, doain</set>
            <set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="slot">body</set>
            <set name="type" addition="medium">Armor</set>
            <set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_MEDIUM, Hide</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="12">12 lb.(manifested)</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
</elements>