<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Items</name>
		<update version="1.0.0">
			<file name="items.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Vibolb/zambonidnd/master/campaign-one/items.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	
	<!-- place your elements here -->
	<element name="Ointment of Sound Sleep" id="ID_DNDC1_ITEM_OINTMENT_OF_SOUND_SLEEP" source="zambonidnd - campaign one" type="Item">
		<description>
			<p>This ointment is prepared by mixing grounded valerian roots and plants with calming and/or 
			sleep-inducing properties (ashwagandha, camomile, hops, kava, lavender, lemon balm, passionflower) 
			in an ointment base (in a ratio of 4.5 gp worth of roots and plants to 5 silver worth of ointment base) 
			and heating it to near boiling temperature for 10 minutes.
			</p>
			<p>It takes one minute to apply one dose to a creature by thoroughly rubbing the ointment behind its hears 
			and on its forehead. For the next 8 hours, the creature has advantage on saving throws against effects that 
			would prevent it from gaining the benefits of its rests.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">herbalist,alchemist,herbs,spices,balm,ointment</set>
			<set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">10</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Frostscreen" id="ID_DNDC1_ITEM_FROSTSCREEN" source="zambonidnd - campaign one" type="Item">
		<description>
			<p>This oily cream is obtained by mixing careful proportions of vegetal oil, water, wax, vinegar and alcohol. 
			   Whereas such mundane ingredients are fairly easy and cheap to provide, this product is typically found with more
			   exotic additives, like rare herbs or spices that provide medicinal benefits to the user. Moreover, it is the knowledge and worksmanship 
			   required to transform all these components into this topical cream that jusitifies its popularity and significant value in cold 
			   climates and exposed ecosystems. For one dose, the typical price is valued between 20 and 25 gold pieces as it takes 
			   about one day to produce with the proper equipment.
			</p>
			<p>It takes ten minutes to apply one dose to a creature by applying and massaging the cream on the skin all over the body. 
			   For the next 8 hours, the creature has advantage on Constitution saving throws to resist the effects of intense cold.
			</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">herbalist,alchemist,herbs,cold,balm,cream</set>
			<set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">25</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
</elements>